MOLDIR SHABIKOVA

Austin, TX +1-347-777-59-21 <u>GitHub</u> <u>moldirshb@gmail.com</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING / FRONTEND DEVELOPER

A Frontend Developer with 2+ years of experience building scalable web applications and maintaining user interfaces. Sharp, resourceful leader, with solid knowledge of JavaScript frameworks and libraries. Proactively seeking ways to refine skills and step into a collaborative team environment to program creative solutions for complex problems.

SKILLS

Programming:

- JavaScript, ES6,
- Express, Node.js, SQL,
- HTML5, CSS3, DOM

Frameworks/Libraries:

- React, React Hooks, Redux,
- Context API, JSON, Jest, Cypress,
- Unit Testing, RESTful APIs,
- Bootstrap, Material UI, SASS

Development/Utilities

- GitHub, Git, Postman,
- Netlify, Heroku, MongoDB,
- Figma, Jira, Agile, Trello
- AWS

EXPERIENCE

EmploSoft — Frontend Developer

Fleet management software company powers fleets' future on a single platform.

June 2021 - Present Chicago, IL

- Created responsive front-end applications using JavaScript and integration of third-party APIs that increased productivity by 20%
- Worked with product managers to architect new frontend features that increased yearly revenue by 15%
- Optimized app performance and loading speed by implementing lazy loading using React Router
- Converted class components into functional components with react hooks enhancing performance by up to 7% by collaborating cross-functionally with other teams
- Built RESTful APIs in the frontend that served data with Node.js, PostgreSQL which improved runtime for fulfilling queries
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources
- Communicated with internal teams and stakeholders, working to determine solutions for the user experience

General Assembly — Software Engineer

August 2020 - April 2021 New York, NY

- Created full-stack applications using React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails
- Worked in teams with git flow to build full-stack applications that include user authorization and full CRUD functionality with React, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, bcrypt, and JWT.
- Planned and built projects according to the agile development cycle from concept to release, both individually and in teams by implementing Git workflow.

EDUCATION

L. N. Gumilyov Eurasian National University - Bachelor of Science

2011 - 2015 Astana, Kazakhstan - Psychology